Perfect binary tree, the perfect binary tree is a type of binary tree in which every internal node
has exactly two child nodes, and all the leaf nodes are at the same level.
Consider this tree, we say about it as a perfect binary tree because all the nodes are at the same
level.
And exactly any internal node has exactly two child nodes.
Let's see examples about that trees.
So these are three, one, two and three.
All the internal nodes have a degree of two.
Recursively, a perfect permanent binary tree can be defined as if a single node has no child or children
like in tree and no one.
It is a perfect binary tree of height, equal to zero.
If a node has at greater than zero, it is a perfect binary tree if both of its up trees are of height
at minus one and are non overlapping.
So this like tree number two and three number three, this is the theory behind the perfect binary tree.
Let's see how we can implement in see the perfect binary tree.
And then in the next video, we are going to implement the perfect binary tree in Joff.
We will start with include a study hall studio and the lip we create the note that we are dealing with
and as a building block of that tree, the node that contains that data and data, we are creating trees
of time integers and struct note to the left and right.
So pointers to the left and pointers to the right.
Now we will create a new method that creates and you know, this method called the new node it contains,
or it passes in data and returns struct node data type, and we reserve the memory milk memory allocation
and then in the memory.
And you know.
And we put inside this note that data that it is at best in the parameters.
We assign that note to the left equal to null and note that are equal to none.
So we till now we have we are creating a note that it's reference to the left is null and reference
to then it is null and the data are contained.
Inside this note is that data that is passed in the arguments of that part of me, of the function.
And we return the note now, calculate the depth, since the perfect binary three depends on the depth
of the tree, so we are going to create an in-depth function.
It returns and end, and it took into parameters the note struck note, and we start by internalizing
the equal to zero.
And we start by looping through all the elements to the left.
So because we need to determine that depth, you can make it to the right, but we prefer making it
to the left.
In order to determine if the first determination of the known slope d-plus plus know the equal note
to the left, so go always go to the left.
So if we if we check off this tree, this is the note.
This note equal node to the left, go to the left every time you loop through this.
This loop, while node does not equal to null, go to the left node equal this go to the left we don't
have, so the will return at three levels.
OK.
Three levels.
It's very simple.
This is the idea behind this calculate depth function.
We create a wrapper function.
We will see it the same as ball is perfect, but this is capital.
B is perfect to meet that route and it will return.
That is perfect.
The small p, OK, but this function just to determine the truth and called another function is perfect,
but with small p.
So this is the small p function.
Ball is perfect.
It took into the parameters the root and integer D and in level and the check if the tree is empty,
if fruit equals equal to null, then return.
If there is no nodes or if the tree is empty, then root equal equal to none.
Now check the presence of children, so root those are left equal, equal to none and ruled that out
equal, equal to none.
Then no nodes, no neither to the left or nor to the right.
Return the equal level level equal equal to the level plus one.
OK, this is how we check that empty tree and we check if there is no other children.
And now if we have.
Route to the left equally, call to null and route to the right.
Equal, equal to null.
But here with or operator, you see the previous step.
We have used that and and operator.
Now we are going to use the owner operator.
If one of the trees to their left subtribes to the left contains.
This is this is.
Translated by making if one of the notes contains a.
Note.
So if the left contain, you know, like, for example, eight and seven and to the right does not contain
anything.
So here for the left secretary, we have a node here, but in the right, somebody does not equal does
not.
We don't have any node.
So for this would not make it a perfect binary tree.
Since a perfect binary tree internal nodes has exactly two children.
Node.
Okay.
Exactly.
Two children?
No.
And all the leaf are at the same level at the same level.
These if we have a new node here and we don't have a node and you node here, they are not on the same
level for that.
We have returned the force.
OK.
Return is false.
We are making it recursive.
Recursively calling is perfect here and passing left the level +1.
And also and and operator.
And we are testing this Boolean expression.
So we have the first let me the first Boolean expression is purely imperfect and we are passing these
parameters left the level +1 and the end operator here.
And this is the second Boolean expression we are checking.
If true, if this return true and this return, the true, true and the true, then this function is
perfect for return.
True, if this function or this expression, boolean expression returns are true.
And we don't have any levels the same.
The left we are no don't have any nested function and no team, but to the right we have nested functions.
And this would return false nested nodes.
True and false, false, false and true false, false and false false.
So we should get through that.
The first expression and the true and the second expression in order to allow us for this function is
perfect to return true.
And tell us that this is a.
Perfect binary.
Three.
OK.
I know that it may be sometime be confusing, but with practice, you may master, you will not, may.
You must and you will master everything.
Let's go and test our code in the main.
So I want from you to put all of these codes, tribe them into your C compiler and start testing your
codes and around them.
Because I need from you to practice to right the codes test your codes to play with codes.
Roland, you note one, two, three, four, five six.
And we are checking if it is perfect truth or not.
OK.
I.
I want from you to test this goat and tell me in the comments below if it is a perfect binary tree or
not.
So for that, we have finished creating a perfect binary tree and see and we are going to make it in
the same concept encoding, but in Java in the next video.
So I'm waiting your comments.
I am waiting on your suggestions.
Any questions?
And I am waiting.
Your answer.
If it is a perfect throughout, this program will blueprint for us a perfect binary tree or not.
So thank you.